[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trien tasa Advanced Training as you all
know I have already published 45 YouTube
videos covering basic level intermediate
level and advanced level
Concepts from couple of videos
have started publishing the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of obstacles and how can
we solve those kind of obstacles by
using trient TSA while automating your
test cases this is our lesson
46 if you like the video please do like
and share the video and don't forget to
Subs to the channel so that you'll get
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank
you in this lesson I'm going to teach
you a realtime scenario where you need
to interact with dynamically changing ID
property elements let us see what is the
obstacle that we need to solve
for so this is our fourth obstacle which
is is two times so let's go for
it so use one module creating two
automated steps to click the button two
times in a
row sounds easier than it is so what do
you mean by that so
here whenever you click this button for
the first time right so if you see the
button name is Click me tox as soon as I
click on this button see now your button
name is changed click me once more right
so once I click one more time that means
your automation job is solved or your
challenge is solved so let's try this
again okay so you have a
button once you click on this button it
changes the name of your button so
that's why the name of the button and
property of the button gets changed for
the second time so you need to click
this button another time then you solve
this automation problem right for that
let's go back to tricenter stasa and as
usual let's scan the
application by using the folder obstacle
right click on this
folder scan click on application
and this is our application select the
application click on
scan now let me maximize the window and
what is the button the button is Click
me 2x so this is the button that we need
to click twice but the button changes
let's see what is the properties of this
button if you see here the property of
button is you have some numeric portion
_ 4
6576 right so remember this and then tag
a you have numeric
underscore sorry it's it's not numeric
you have a characters underscore numeric
value 4 657 six so let me close this I
don't want to save this I just want to
close this and let me click this button
one time right now let me rescan this
particular application right click click
on
application and select the application
click on
scan so if you see the button now and
the properties of
button now your button name is Click me
once more let's see the property of this
button so you can see here the property
of button has changed see here numeric
sorry your alphabets underscore now your
numeric portion got changed 84
68 so how can we solve this this
particular challenge to click the button
twice so for that let's close this again
so let me
just click on this and then let's try
this again okay so now let us go back to
our trient tasa and now let me scan the
application I would like to capture the
object at initial
stage
itself before you click the button for
the first time right click on
scan and
here
let's select the button click me
2x as I told you the button has an ID
and this
ID gets changed to the another numeric
portion here after underscore so that's
why I cannot keep this as is instead
remove that changing portion of your
property and replace with hasri which is
a regular expression this regular
expression hasri is used Whenever there
is a dynamic portion this can
handle rmd uncore after that after
underscore you can have any alphabet or
numeric portion it doesn't
matter it recognize the object even
though you have any number or any
character after underscore so I would
like to replace that static value with a
regular expression hasri and click on
Okay so done now let's rename this
module with the name of your
obstacle this is my obstacle name copy
this and rename this so it's a best
practice to rename the
module so that it makes a logical sense
okay so now let's save the module
so close your X scan so let's go back to
renasa now you can see this is my new
module that I have scanned click me 2x
so let me create a new test case now
under obstacle
folder right
click create a test
case name this as your obstacle
name double click on this so now let me
drag and drop the new module that we
scanned drag and drop
here so
here for the first time you need to
click on click me 2x right for that pass
this x now again I want to click on this
same button right but the button
property gets changed
drag this same module and drop into the
same test case one more
time and here I would like to rename
this as click button once more and this
step
is
Click
button for first
time right so here again for the second
time pass X
so now this is done now let's save the
test case and mark the test case work
state as complete completed right and
now let me run this test case and see if
we can click the button
twice see it clicked on once it clicked
second time I would like to do one thing
okay so let's do one thing let's go back
here I would like to
use the some other click function so
that you can
[Music]
see whether it is clicking or not I
would like to use click function which
uses the keyboard action so that your
cursor will be placed onto the
button so let's run this again one more
time
see your cursor moved to the button and
it clicked one more time so that means
now you solve this automation problem so
whenever you are automating your test
cases during that time if you have any
dynamically changing ID
properties dynamically changing partial
text value or partial value of your ID
then you can solve the problem by using
this approach this is medium level
obstacle but going forward we'll move to
hard categorization of
obstacles so if you have any queries
leave your queries in the comment box
I'll try to respond to your queries hope
you all understand how can we solve an
obstacle while automating your test
cases where you have to interact with
the elements for which the element
properties are dynamically
changing please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos please do like and share the
video thank you
[Music]